A Guide to the Tazewell family papers, 1623-1930
Library of Virginia
- 30 September 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Bill of exchange-pay to Samuel and Peter Christian
- 30 September 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  invoice for Madera wine to Mr. Thomson on account of William H. Thompson
- 15 October 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell finances with Bank of Virginia
- 15 October 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  William Wirt to Littleton Waller Tazewell-thanks Tazewell for his opinion-wishes Tazewell would undertake the military work because he has a good understanding of it-Wirt too busy
- 19 October 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  James Weasser[?] of Baltimore to Littleton Waller Tazewell-concerning legal business-mentions John Scott a Baltimore attorney
- 27 October 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell account with William Francis
- 29 November 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Jacob Klein and James Thornburn-promissory note for $400 to the Union Insurance Company of Norfolk
- 30 November 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Jacob Klein and James Thornburn-promissory note for $148.50 to the Union Insurance Company of Norfolk
- 30 November 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Jacob Klein and James Thornburn-promissory note for $112.50 to the Union Insurance Company of Norfolk
- 23 December 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Jacob Klein and James Thornburn-promissory note for $140 to the Union Insurance Company of Norfolk
- 23 December 1818 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Jacob Klein and James Thornburn-promissory note for $210 to the Union Insurance Company of Norfolk
- January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  expenses for the month of January-Littleton Waller Tazewell
- 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Corporation of Norfolk in account with J. Nivison [and T. Reiley] commissioners for tobacco warehouse--located in oversize box 14, folder 9
- 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  account of the borough of Norfolk with J. Nivison and T. Reiley commissioners for tobacco warehouse
- 1 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  receipt from Robert E. Steed to Littleton Waller Tazewell for payment of $25 for tuition for his sons with Rev. George Halson-note on back states paid 5 January
- 2 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  draft for $1250 from Littleton Waller Tazewell to Albert Allmand (treasurer)-drawn on the Bank of the United States
- 2 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  John Swartwout of New York to Littleton Waller Tazewell-received Tazewell's check for money owed him out of the Algerine captures
- 13 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  acknowledgement of receipt by Giles B. Cooke having received $1093.76 from George Loyall, William Loyall, Benjamin Pollard, Eliza Pollard, Cary Selden, and Frances Selden-money owed by George Loyall dec'd to Mariam Talbot
- 19 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell account with Caleb Bonsal-paid on date-received by John H. Nash
- 20 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  deed between Ann T. Davis, Maria T. Hansford, Hugh Pannell, Courtney Pannell, William Pannell, Sarah C. Pannell, and William H. Bennock on the one part and Littleton Waller Tazewell on the other-a lot in Norfolk for $10,000-includes anything on it-recorded 27 January in Norfolk Hustings court
- 22 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Hugh Pannell and William Pannell-receipt to Littleton Waller Tazewell for $2500 paid-1st payment of $10,000 for property purchased (see above)
- 26 January 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  accounts-Littleton Waller Tazewell with grocer Robert E. Steed (3)
- 1 February 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  protest made by Littleton Waller Tazewell as Notary Public for failure to pay a promissory note for $255 dated 29 July 1818 by Jacob Klein, James Thorburn, and W. A. Armistead to Union Insurance Company
- 11 February 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  attachment-court papers
- 12 February 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  certificate for stock (24 shares) for Robert Hines in the James River Steam Boat Company
- 25 February 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  J. D. Elliott to Littleton Waller Tazewell-finally received Tazewell's letter-took steps for payment-congratulates him on Gosport getting docking and fitting establishment
- 1 March 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  deed for land in Norfolk County between Magdalen Magagnor to Richard Powell-William T. Nivison trustee-deed of trust recorded 16 September 1819
- 12 April 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  account of estate of John Nivison with Caleb Bonsal-Bonsal notes received payment
- 21 April 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Edgecombe County, North Carolina, court records--located in oversize box 13, folder 12
- 26 May 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  court papers involving the Ritchie family of North Carolina-depositions for Williamsburg District Court
- 26 May 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  account and receipt for property owned by William T. Nivison and insured by the Mutual Assurance Society
- 29 May 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  account of Mrs. Tazewell at F. Brette and Vincent-also notes payment received
- 2 June 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Charles Carter in King William County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-concerning a suit that Tazewell's nephew Richard Corbin is involved with
- 11 June 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  William T. Nivison to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Williamsburg-regarding some suits he's working on
- 30 June 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  United States against three trunks threads imported by James Arbuthnoth-collectors office Norfolk
- 30 June 1819 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  James Heron of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-has an offer for Tazewell's U.S. stock on 12 month credit
- 3 July 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Promissory note for $2028.45 from John Nivison to John Anderson-notices of payment on inside back (1821-1822)
- 18 July 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  deed between William H. Thompson and the Bank of the United States for property in Elizabeth City County-to cover his debts with the bank-acknowledged in Norfolk Clerk's office 19 February 1820
- 24 July 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  John Nivison in Saratoga NY to Littleton Waller Tazewell-concerning personal and business matters Tazewell is handling for him-John Nivison and William T. Nivison are traveling to Northern springs to try to restore John's health
- 26 July 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  account-John Nivison with Samuel Vickery
- 2 August 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  William T. Nivison in Ballston NY to his sister Louisa Nivison in Norfolk-discussing his travels in Northern springs-personal news
- 7 August 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  John Nivison in Ballston NY to his wife Sarah Nivison-personal news-discussing his health and the spa
- 16 August 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  list of notes deposited in the Bank of Virginia by Littleton Waller Tazewell
- 26 August 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  William T. Nivison in Ballston NY to Louisa Nivison-glad to get letter-prefers Norfolk to the NY springs-his disappointing encounter with a Boston Belle-light humorous discussion of the women at Ballston-another tale of romance (not involving him)-visit of King Joseph (Bonaparte) to Ballston-two French cooks reunite after not seeing each other for many years-discusses William Short and is peculiar bachelor habits-also Mr. Pollock-WTN doesn't want to be a bachelor-a poem to a Miss W---- Colonel [James] Talmadge at Ballston, he's a drinker
- 2 September 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  John Nivison and William T. Nivison in Albany NY to Sarah Nivison-traveling to Lebanon Springs NY-John--asks her to pass along a request to Tazewell-health-William-his father's health-John needs to control what he eats-however believe his health is coming back-John wants to go home-traveling to Lebanon Springs-will be in New York soon
- 16 September 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  William T. Nivison in Lancaster PA to Louisa Nivison-missed her letter in NY-but left because of yellow fever-discusses their trip through Troy NY-looked for their acquaintances the van Brackles-trip to Albany nice, but not Albany-while there enjoyed hospitality of van Rensalaers, "Lord Mayor" and the "Patrune" [Patroon]-nice time at Lebanon springs
- 21 September 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Benjamin Thomas or Hormans of the Navy Department to Commander Arthur Sinclair at Norfolk-orders a court-martial for John Barrat charged with desertion-asks him to appoint a judge advocate (Tazewell?)
- 23 September 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  John Nivison in Georgetown DC to Sarah Nivison-serious carriage accident-involving him, William T. Nivison, and Benjamin Watkins Leigh-got others out, he was trapped-finally rescued-later went Washington-saw Decatur who invited them to visit-will when feels better-William T. Nivison also gives his account of the accident-thankful that no one was hurt-believes that his father's health was improved by the trip to New York
- 24 September 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to unknown recipient-naval commission-mentions Decatur-concerning courts-martial-situation of the recipient and naval discipline
- 25 September 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  charge and specification of charge exhibited against John Barrat-naval court-martial-Norfolk
- 2 October 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  William T. Nivison in Richmond to Louisa Nivison-they are in Richmond-Catharine and Joe's new son-stayed with the Decaturs in Washington-had a great time-dined with William Wirt-Richmond is gloomy-not glittery like before-suffering during the hard times-John Myers up by steamboat-looks desperate-say hello to the family
- 13 October 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  true copy of a letter from T. Wrorkley [?] to John Taylor stating that his ship is leaving for England and requesting that he board without delay-29 October 1819-notes that Taylor had brought "spirits" which he drank from a lot and gave some to the crew-not sure when letter was originally written
- 22 October 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  T. Wrorkley [?] to Littleton Waller Tazewell-information about John Taylor's voyage aboard the Isabella in May 1819-ship had to return to Norfolk rather than go to England-Taylor got off before Norfolk-had supplies aboard-see true copy of letter of Taylor to Wrorkley [?] copied 19 October
- 9 November 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  will of Jonathan Beard copied from Baltimore County will book-original written 31 January 1806
- 12 November 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  deposition before the mayor of Baltimore, Edward Johnson, by Rev. John Hargrove, Colonel Mathew McLaughlin, Ann Barling, Sarah Barling, Henry Howard, Caroline French, and Hannah E. Hargrove-stating they were present at the home of John Hargrove 26 December 1806 when Harriet E. Hargrove married Jonathan Beard
- 13 November 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  John Hargrove certifies that he married Dr. Joel Hopkins and Harriet E. Beard (widow of Jonathan Beard) in matrimony 30 October 1817
- 14 November 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  deposition before the mayor of Baltimore by James A. Buchanan of the firm Smith and Buchanan that Jonathan Beard was constantly employed by the company before his death sometime in 1806-that Beard lived in Baltimore and had no other home when ashore-states that Beard married daughter of Rev. Hargrove before his last voyage
- December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  memorandum of agreement on sale of "Old Plantation" between Edward Wilson of Somerset County and William T. Nivison of Norfolk
- December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  deed from John Custis Wilson and Edward H. C. Wilson of Somerset County MD to William T. Nivison of Norfolk for Old Plantation in Northampton County
- 6 December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  power of attorney from Joel Hopkins of Ann Arundal County MD to James Rudden of Portsmouth to reclaim property for him
- 11 December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  power of attorney from William T. Nivison to John Nivison concerning the purchase of Old Plantation from Edward Wilson of Somerset county MD
- 14 December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  agreement between Edward Wilson of Somerset County MD and John Nivison attorney for William T. Nivison concerning William T. Nivison's purchase of "Old Plantation"
- 14 December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  deed between Edward H. C. Wilson of Somerset County MD and William T. Nivison of Norfolk for Old Plantation in Northampton County-recorded Northampton County 9 May 1820
- 28 December 1819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  promissory note from John Nivison to William T. Nivison for $2000
- 3 and 8 August 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell concerning his account with the Farmers' Bank of Virginia
- 17 and 18 February 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  17 and 18 February 1820-rough copies of two letters from Littleton Waller Tazewell to Robert Walker-steam boat company affairs-James River Steam Boat Company not doing too bad-would do better if not for Petersburg-Newbern Steam Boat Company not doing well at all-discussion of the steam boat business in Norfolk waters
- 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  eleven receipts and accounts of the estate of John Nivison
- 7 February 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia for $270 to be paid to Robert Saunders or bearer signed John Nivison
- 26 February 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia for $148 from John Nivison to William T. Nivison
- 29 February 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Promissory note for $2000 from John Nivison to William T. Nivison
- 4 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Nathaniel Macon in the U.S. Senate to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Washington-asks Tazewell to visit in the evening-has some items he'd like Tazewell to take to John Randolph in Baltimore
- 5 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia to pay William T. Nivison or bearer $100 from John Nivison
- 13 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia for $46 to be paid to Mr. Babbington from John Nivison
- 15 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  agreement between Edward H. C. Wilson and William T. Nivison concerning "Old Plantation"
- 20 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia for $50 to be paid to William Sharp or bearer from John Nivison
- 28 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  -John Mettatier [?] of Prince Edward County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asks Tazewell to handle three suits which will be in the Chancery Court in Williamsburg-will send details
- 29 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia for $270.58 to be paid to John Henderson or bearer from John Nivison
- 30 March 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  draft on the Bank of Virginia for $25 to be paid to Keziah [?] or bearer from John Nivison
- 6 April 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  bill from Tennison's Hotel in Washington DC--$20 for time from 28 March to 6 April
- 11 April 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Robert B. Gibson of Nottoway County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-has two cases going to court in Williamsburg Chancery by order of judge of the Superior Court of Chancery in Richmond-lays out the cases for Tazewell-asks for his help
- 12 April 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Francis Corbin in Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-sends $25-laments that no one has money all are broke "The times! the times! no dividends!-no crops making money-blames those running banks-discusses allotment of land in a case-bemoans the current government as bad and corrupt
- 27 April 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  notes in a suit against the Commonwealth
- 29 April 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Will of John Nivison
- 2 May 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  William Bernard of possibly Frederick [now Clark] County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asks for legal help
- 12 May 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  letter from William T. Nivison to Maria Stokes of Philadelphia containing a draft for $54 on the Bank of Virginia signed by John Nivison-letter written by William T. Nivison-John Nivison's last signature ever-signed 12 May, died 13 May
- 13 May 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  John Nivison in account with James Woodward-last entry, 13 May 1820, is for Nivison's coffin
- 23 May 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  John Hargrove of Baltimore to Littleton Waller Tazewell-regarding the estates of Captain Jonathan Beard and of Captain Richard Beard, specifically property in Portsmouth-bill has been filed and his daughter, widow of Jonathan, now married to Joel Hopkins, asks for Tazewell's legal help (see documents above 12-14 November 1819)
- 30 May 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell account with S. B. Werckmuller
- June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  rule docket for June court
- 2 June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  check for $1277.70 on Bank of Virginia from W. T. Nivison to Executors [probably of his father's estate] or bearer
- 14 June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Mutual Assurance Society Policy 2794 to Sarah Nivison, Louisa Nivison, and William T. Nivison--located in oversize box 14, folder 12
- 14 June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Mutual Assurance Society Policy 2793 to Sarah Nivison, Louisa Nivison, and William T. Nivison--located in oversize box 14, folder 12
- 17 June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Francis Walker Gilmer in Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asks for Tazewell's notes concerning Long v. Colson
- 17 June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  monies of Littleton Waller Tazewell to Bank of Virginia
- 21 June 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  [?] Brunet of Norfolk to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Williamsburg-sends the last will of Major James Williams-asks for Tazewell to handle a case
- 1 July 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  receipt to Littleton Waller Tazewell for $25 for 3 month tuition for his sons to be tutored by Rev. George Halson-Robert E. Steed by J. E. [?] Wilkinson
- 12 August 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to Thomas Derbyshire of Philadelphia-enclosing a note on the Bank of Pennsylvania for $22.07
- 22 August 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Captain William Chowning of sloop Intercourse account with Alexander Rind [?]-shipping 2000 bushels of coal for Davenport and Allen
- 24 August 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  deed from Rosanna Murphey to Mary Cosby-slaves
- 28 August 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Ann Nivison Tazewell to her sister Sarah S. Skipwith of Mecklenburg County-their sister Louisa is at Green Springs in Goochland County-visited by Mr. Whittle who plans to move his family to Mecklenburg-local and family news-recipe for yeast
- 30 August 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  account of William T. Nivison with William Plume and company
- 7 September 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  bill of lading-6 boxes of marble shipped by Richard North aboard the sloop Ann Eliza Davis going from Philadelphia to Norfolk-shipped to James Taylor
- 11 September 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to an unknown recipient-genealogical information on the Littleton family which settled on the eastern shore
- 1 October 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  circular letter concerning the creation of The Amercan Academy of Language and Belles Lettres-includes a constitution
- 7 October 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  John Inskeep [?] of Philadelphia to James Taylor of Norfolk-regarding the tombstone for John Nivison shipped from Philadelphia-the cost
- 10 October 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  promissory note from Nathaniel Hickman and Thomas Fitchel to William T. Nivison, executor of John Nivison $15.55
- 16 October 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  James Taylor account with William Babbington for wharfage of 6 boxes stone from Ann Eliza Davis (sloop)-50 cents
- 26 October 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  John Inskeep [?] of Philadelphia to James Taylor of Norfolk acknowledging receipt of $205.97 for tombstone for John Nivison
- November 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  William T. Nivison account with clerk of Northampton County
- 28 November 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Will of William T. Nivison-inside notes on his debts and money in the bank-copy of will
- 29 November 1820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  inventory of the estate of John Nivison in Northampton County-includes list of slaves and value (finished 29 July 1820)-inventory of the estate of John Nivison in Princess Anne County-includes list of slaves and value (finished 25 September 1820)-recorded in Norfolk quarterly court 29 November 1820
- 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4 (Begin Misc. reel #673))
  account of the estate of John Nivison with the clerk of Norfolk Borough
- 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  receipt from Peter Land, sheriff, to Littleton Waller Tazewell for payment of Parish Levy for 1821 and 1822
- January 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  David Milhado (dec'd) account with John W. Southgate
- 25 January 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-received several letters from Randolph-apologizes for not answering them-regrets that a pamphlet about Decatur was published-not a good idea-spends time on his plantation-provides argument he made in a case before the Chief Justice regarding neutral courts and prizes
- 3 February 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  F. Vincent to Jane Collins, both of Norfolk-regarding notes he received from her in discharging Mr. Carraway's claims
- 12 February 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William Floyd Jr. to William T. Nivison-Floyd's dogs killed his sheep-other trouble with livestock-is going to sow his oats-invites Nivison for a visit
- 1 March 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William T. Nivison to Mr. Absalom concerning the hire of Nivison's slave Sam Barber--$60 for 5 March to 1 January or $2 a week-note on back states gave him up 15 June but agreed to take him back for $1.50 a week
- 1 April 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William T. Nivison account with the Mutual Assurance Society-marked received payment by Benjamin Pollard
- 9 April 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  note from R. McCandlish in Williamsburg to Miles King of Norfolk-sending a copy of a deed that King had asked for
- 23 April 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 15 May 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William Waller of Williamsburg to Littleton Waller Tazewell-regarding Indian Fields estate-whether Tazewell would buy it or not-will not accept payment for an old bond that he and his brother found-could Tazewell write up a new bond?
- 1 June 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William T. Nivison to Louisa Nivison in Northampton County-family news-execution of two Spaniards
- 6 June 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-thanks him for his letter-impressed with his writing-fatherly advice
- 13 June 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  dinner invitation from Mr. and Mrs. Nathaniel Macon to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Washington
- 16 June 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William L. Cardell of New York to Littleton Waller Tazewell-the American Academy of Language and Belles Lettres-officers and members-Tazewell voted in unanimously-see circular dated 1 October 1820
- 28 June 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Daniel Brent of the Department of State forwards a letter to Littleton Waller Tazewell
- 29 June 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  statement from William Smith that Robertson [?] cut wheat 3 days at Lawsons in Princess Anne County
- 3 July 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  account of William T. Nivison with William Parsons for best pattern sights plated-received 50 cents from Nivison by William Floyd
- 6 July 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William T. Nivison in account with Thomas F. Nixon (butcher)
- 1 August 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell in account with Henry McDowell for candles
- 10 August 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  receipts to John Nivison and William T. Nivison for payments to the Northampton County sheriff
- 17 August 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William F. Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-regarding a deed of trust and lien that Tazewell has on property of Harry Tompkins-Edward Taylor would buy the land under that sale by Tazewell
- 20 August 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  receipt from J. Newcomb to Littleton Waller Tazewell for payment of $16.80
- 21 August 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  account, William T. Nivison with Josiah Willis
- 31 August 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  James Scaife requests that William T. Nivison pay William Smith $1.25 for picking mill stones
- 12 September 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  William F. Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-again concerning Tazewell's lien on property of Harry Tompkins-Edward Taylor would like Tazewell to enforce deed of trust
- 20 September 1821 (Box 4, Folder 4)